# John "Tyler" Maxwell

tylermaxwell.webdev@gmail.com | (770) 315-6761 | Dallas, GA 30157

Portfolio: <a href="http://tyler-maxwell.github.io/">http://tyler-maxwell.github.io/</a> | GitHub: <a href="http://github.com/tyler-maxwell">http://github.com/tyler-maxwell</a>

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/tylermaxwell1990/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/tylermaxwell1990/</a>

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with 5 years of experience. Strong verbal and written communication skills. Works well both with a team and independently. Learns new technologies very quickly. Past training in philosophy provides the skills to think outside the box and develop creative solutions.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Handlebars, React, JSON, Node, Express, SQL, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, WordPress, GIT, Github, APIs, MVC architecture, computer science fundamentals.

### **PROJECTS**

## Magic: The Gathering Collection Tracker

Full-Stack Developer/Project Manager | Firebase, ¡Query, AJAX, APIs | GitHub | Live

Stores, organizes, and searches Magic: The Gathering playing card collections for individual user accounts

#### Eat-Da-Burger!

Full-Stack Developer | MySQL, Node, Express, Handlebars | <u>GitHub</u> | <u>Live</u>

Utilizes a homemade ORM to create a burger logger that conforms to the MVC design pattern.

### **Clicky Game**

Front-End Developer | React, JSON | GitHub | Live

Uses React to dynamically render clickable cards from JSON data and track user clicks

### **EXPERIENCE**

Millis Transfer, Inc. | Cartersville, GA | September 2016 – December 2017

OTR Tractor-Trailer Operator

Transferable Skills: time management, attention to detail, adaptability

# Office of Alumni Affairs at Kennesaw State University | Kennesaw, GA | October 2014 – May 2015

Student Administrative Assistant

Transferable Skills: communication, problem-solving, adaptability

### Philosophy Student Association | Kennesaw, GA | September 2009 – December 2015

President | Vice President | Secretary | Webmaster

Transferable Skills: leadership, communication, team building, project management, public speaking, training

#### **EDUCATION**

Georgia Institute of Technology | Atlanta, GA | May 2018 – November 2018

Coding Bootcamp for Web Development

Kennesaw State University | Kennesaw, GA | August 2008 – December 2015

Bachelor of Arts in Philosophy